Let’s move on to exploit-exercises stack level 5.
让我们继续探索漏斗 - 练习堆栈 5级。
You should have watched the previous videos to understand how we got here.
你应该看过以前的视频 了解我们如何到达这里。
The challenge description says
挑战描述说
Stack5 is a standard buffer overflow, this time introducing shellcode.
Stack5是标准的缓冲区溢出，这个 时间介绍shellcode。
And the hints are:
提示是：
that, it might be easier to use someone elses shellcode.
那个，使用别人可能更容易 的shellcode。
That is also what we will do.
这也是我们将要做的。
And
和
If debugging the shellcode, use the “int3” instruction with the opcode hex CC, to stop
如果调试shellcode，请使用“int3” 使用操作码十六进制CC的指令，停止
the program executing and return to the debugger.
程序执行并返回调试器。
And that is very helpful.
这非常有帮助。
Ok, let’s have a look at this code.
好的，我们来看看这段代码。
It is surprisingly small.
它非常小。
There is just one function call to gets(), which we know allows us to overwrite data
只有一个函数调用gets（）， 我们知道允许我们覆盖数据
on the stack.
在堆栈上。
So how do we get from no functionality of the program, to a root shell?
那么我们如何从没有功能获得 程序，到root shell？
So put on your wizard's hat, because we will do some magic.
所以戴上你的巫师的帽子，因为我们会 做一些魔术。
Let’s open this program in gdb, and let’s just throw a long string against it.
让我们在gdb中打开这个程序吧 只是扔一个长串反对它。
To do that let’s already prepare our exploit script.
要做到这一点，我们已经准备好了我们的漏洞 脚本。
So first we want to find the offset that allows us to control the instruction pointer.
所以首先我们要找到允许的偏移量 我们来控制指令指针。
I’d like to use a simple pattern like the alphabet.
我想用一个像 字母表。
So I create this exploit variable and assign the long string to it, and then print that.
所以我创建这个漏洞变量并分配 把长长的字符串放到上面，然后打印出来。
Now redirect the output of this script into a file, which we then can use as input for
现在将此脚本的输出重定向到 一个文件，然后我们可以将其用作
gdb.
GDB。
Before we execute the program, let’s create a breakpoint at the return of main.
在执行程序之前，我们先创建 在主程序返回时的一个断点。
And let’s define a hook, like we have done in a previous video.
让我们定义一个钩子，就像我们所做的那样 在以前的视频中。
Define hook stop, and we want to display the current instruction that will be executed
定义钩子停止，我们希望显示 将要执行的当前指令
next, so examine one instruction at the location of eip.
接下来，在该位置检查一条指令 EIP。
And then examine 8 words as hex from the stack.
然后从堆栈中检查8个十六进制单词。
And end.
结束。
Then execute it, and we hit the breakpoint at the return.
然后执行它，我们就到达了断点 在返回。
The next line shows us how the stack looks like right now.
下一行显示堆栈的外观 就像现在一样。
And when we execute the ret, we will jump to the address that was on the stack before.
当我们执行RET时，我们会跳 到堆栈上以前的地址。
So no execute it again with the alphabet.
所以不可以用字母表再执行一次。
We are at the return again, and we can see that we have overwritten stuff on the stack.
我们又回来了，我们可以看到 我们已经覆盖了堆栈上的内容。
So now we try to return to address hex 54545454.
现在我们试着返回地址hex 545454。
Which is obviously invalid, so we get a Segmentation Fault.
这显然是无效的，所以我们得到一个分段 Fault。
And with examine as string, we can see that we have overwritten the return pointer with
使用examine作为字符串，我们可以看到 我们已经用覆盖返回指针
T’s.
T的
So let’s update our exploit script.
所以让我们更新我们的漏洞脚本。
This will be our padding.
这将是我们的填充物。
And we create the variable eip, which we can use to control the instruction pointer and
我们创建变量eip，我们可以 用于控制指令指针和
jump anywhere we want.
想跳到哪里就跳。
And I use struct to create a binary string from the address again.
我使用struct创建一个二进制字符串 再次从地址。
So struct.pack.
所以结构。
But where do we want to jump to?
但是我们想跳到哪里呢？
We don’t have any win() function like in previous levels.
我们没有类似的win（）函数 以前的级别。
Do you have any idea where we could jump to?
你知道我们可以跳到哪里吗？
I think I will give you a second to think about this.
我想我会让你思考一下 关于这个。
Right, we can just jump to the stack where we control data.
好吧，我们可以跳到那堆 我们控制数据。
So obviously we could place some assembler code there.
所以很明显我们可以安排一些装配工 代码在那里。
Now let’s find a good address.
现在我们找个好地址。
We could just jump right after the instruction pointer we control.
我们可以在接到指令后马上跳下去 我们控制的指针。
To do that just run again, execute the ret and have a look at the stack pointer.
要做到这一点，只需再次运行，执行ret 看看栈指针。
So that is the address we want to jump to.
所以这就是我们要跳转到的地址。
And now we have to append code that we want to execute after the return pointer, so why
现在我们必须附加我们想要的代码 在返回指针之后执行，所以为什么
not use the opcode CC, the int3, they were suggesting in the challenge description.
不使用操作码cc，int3，它们是 在挑战描述中提出建议。
Let’s also quickly have a look at the intel instruction reference.
让我们也快速了解一下Intel 说明参考。
Let’s search for “Int 3”.
让我们搜索“int 3”。
Ok mmhh… call itnerrupt procedure.
好的，嗯…叫它中断程序。
what else do we find.
我们还能找到什么。
In this table about general exceptions it calls this instruction breakpoint?
在本表中，关于一般例外情况 调用此指令断点？
Huuu, that’s interesting.
胡，真有趣。
Ok and here is the description of it.
好的，这是对它的描述。
Interrupt number 3, traps to debugger.
中断3，陷阱到调试器。
And down here it reads:
下面是：
The INT 3 instruction is a special one byte opcode (CC) that is intended for calling the
int 3指令是一个特殊的单字节 用于调用
debug exception handler.
调试异常处理程序。
(This one byte form is valuable because it can be used to replace the first byte of any
（这个单字节形式很有价值，因为它 可用于替换
instruction with a breakpoint, including other one byte instructions, without over-writing
具有断点的指令，包括其他 单字节指令，无过度写入
other code).
其他代码）。
wooooh.
哇哦。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, how do you think gdb works?
嗯，你认为gdb是如何工作的？
Or any other debugger for that matter?
或者其他的调试器？
How can you just stop the CPU from executing something.
怎样才能阻止CPU执行 某物。
Or just step one instruction?
或者只是一个指令？
Actually a debugger can just use the INT 3 instruction.
实际上，调试程序只能使用int 3 指令。
Let’s make an example.
让我们举个例子。
We just created a breakpoint at this ret.
我们刚刚在这个ret上创建了一个断点。
What we actually did was, we replaced this return instruction in memory with int 3.
我们实际做的是，我们换了这个 用int 3返回内存中的指令。
And when the CPU reached this instruction, an exception was raised.
当CPU达到这个指令时， 引发了异常。
Or in hardware terms an interrupt got triggered, which stopped the CPU from continuing excecuting
或者在硬件方面，一个中断被触发， 它阻止了CPU继续执行
this and called an interrupt handler (similar to how a syscall caused an interrupt and execution
并调用一个中断处理程序（类似 系统调用如何导致中断和执行
continued somewhere else).
继续其他地方）。
And we can now decide how we want to handle this exception.
现在我们可以决定如何处理 这个例外。
And if we are a debugger we would now replace this INT 3 instruction again with the original
如果我们是一个调试器，我们现在将替换 这个int 3指令与原来的
value, the return instruction.
值，返回指令。
That can also be used as an anti reversing technique.
也可以用来做倒车 技术。
Because a regular application will not use the CC instruction.
因为常规应用程序不会使用 CC指令。
So a malware might constantly scan itself for the CC opcode, and if it finds it, it
所以恶意软件可能会不断扫描自己 对于CC操作码，如果找到它，它
knows that somebody attached a debugger and tried to set a breakpoint.
知道有人附加了一个调试器 试图设置断点。
And now we will use the CC in our payload.
现在我们将在有效载荷中使用CC。
So let’s append a couple of CCs after the overwritten return pointer.
所以我们在 覆盖返回指针。
Don’t forget to write the output of the script into the exploit file.
别忘了写 在漏洞文件中编写脚本。
And then test this in gdb.
然后在gdb中测试这个。
Ok run again.
好的，再跑。
We can see that we stopped at the ret and we see the address where we would return to.
我们可以看到我们在退房处停了下来， 我们看到了我们将返回的地址。
And when we continue now, we pop the instruction pointer value from the stack, thus continue
当我们继续时，我们弹出指令 堆栈中的指针值，因此继续
excecuting on the stack, where we have our INT 3 instrucitons, and as you can see, gdb
在堆栈上执行，我们的 Int 3 Instructions，如您所见，GDB
stopped because it received a signal SIGTRAP, a trace/breakpoint trap.
停止，因为它接收到信号信号陷阱， 跟踪/断点陷阱。
Cool.
酷。
This way we know that we have code execution, because we successfully injected an assembler
这样我们就知道我们有代码执行， 因为我们成功地注入了一个汇编程序
instruction.
指令。
Now does that work without gdb too?
现在，没有gdb这也行吗？
Let’s try it…
让我们试试……
But we get an illegal instruction?
但是我们得到了非法指令？
That is not what we should see.
这不是我们应该看到的。
We should get the breakpoint message.
我们应该得到断点消息。
Let’s open it in gdb here and try it again.
让我们在gdb中打开它，然后再试一次。
Still illegal instruction.
仍然是非法指令。
Let’s set the hooks and the breakpoints like in the other gdb session.
让我们设置钩子和断点 就像在其他GDB会话中一样。
Ok run.
好吧，跑吧。
mhmh…
嗯…
The addresses on the stack are not the same.
堆栈上的地址不相同。
Why are they different?
为什么它们不同？
Let’s do something crazy.
让我们做些疯狂的事情吧。
Print the whole stack.
打印整个堆栈。
I just print a thousand strings or something.
我只印了一千串或其他东西。
Let’s se what we get.
让我们看看我们得到了什么。
Ok first we have some gibebrish.
好的，首先我们有一些基代数。
Let’s go further.
我们走得更远。
UUUh… see.
嗯……看。
Now we get some interesting stuff.
现在我们得到一些有趣的东西。
Let’s do the same in the other gdb session.
让我们在另一个gdb会话中做同样的事情。
This looks like the environment variables.
这看起来像环境变量。
For example here us the USER environment variable that we have used in a previous programming
例如，这里是用户环境变量 我们在以前的程序中使用的
video.
视频。
Mh and when you look at the addresses, they are still diferent.
当你看到地址时，他们 仍然是不同的。
So let’s look a bit further down.
让我们再往下看。
mh! down here they are the same.
嗯！在这里他们是一样的。
So between here and the environemnt variables above there mus be something different.
所以在这里和环境变量之间 上面应该有一些不同的东西。
And when you look closely, you can see that the PWD environment variable, the current
当你仔细观察的时候，你会发现 pwd环境变量，当前
working directory is different.
工作目录不同。
They have a different length.
它们的长度不同。
So obviously the one execution environment needs more space on the stack to store this
很明显，只有一个执行环境 堆栈上需要更多空间来存储此
path.
路径。
And thus pushing the stack further up.
从而进一步推高堆栈。
No wonder that the stack addresses are not the same anymore.
难怪堆栈地址不是 再也一样了。
So how can we cope with that?
那么我们如何应对呢？
There are a couple of techniques that you can use to get a bit more control over the
有一些技巧 可以用来对
stack.
栈。
For example by removing all environment variables before executing a binary.
例如，通过删除所有环境变量 在执行二进制文件之前。
But there is another very easy but effective trick.
但是还有另一个很容易但很有效的方法 诡计。
here is a hint:
这里有一个提示：
nop, nop, nop, nop, nop
不，不，不，不，不，不
Riiiight… a nop slide…
好的……没有幻灯片……
Let’s just add a looooot of NOP instructions.
让我们添加一个loooot的nop指令。
A Nop instruction performs no operation.
nop指令不执行任何操作。
And it has the opcode hex 90.
它有操作码hex 90。
And instead of picking a very specific stack address, let’s just pick one that we hope
而不是选择一个非常具体的堆栈 地址，让我们选一个我们希望的
hits our nops.
击中我们的NoP。
So run again.
所以再次运行。
Now we can see we have a lot of NOPs on the stack.
现在我们可以看到我们在 栈。
And the address we will jump to points somewhere else further down.
我们将跳转到某个地点的地址 再往下走。
If we look at more of the stack, we can see that it points almost right in the middle
如果我们看更多的堆栈，我们可以看到 它几乎就在中间
of the nops.
NOPS的。
So let’s just single step forwards.
让我们向前迈出一步。
And now we happily slide down the nop slide until we reach the bottom with our traps!
现在我们高兴地滑下了nop滑道 直到我们用陷阱到达底部！
Boom.
繁荣。
Cool.
酷。
And that also works now outside of gdb.
这也在GDB之外起作用。
Now instead of CC, we want to execute something useful.
现在，我们要执行一些操作，而不是CC 有用的。
So let’s look for some shellcode.
所以我们来找一些外壳代码。
As the challenge description said, it’s best to reuse shellcode from other people.
正如挑战描述所说，这是 最好是重用别人的shell代码。
I really like the collection of shellcode from shellstorm.
我真的很喜欢贝壳代码的收集 来自暴风雪。
Shellstorm has a lot of different kind of shellcode, for a lot of different system.
暴风雪有很多不同的种类 Shellcode，用于许多不同的系统。
So we are looking for a Linux Intel 32bit shellcode.
所以我们要找的是LinuxIntel32bit 贝壳代码。
FreeBSD, Linux on ARM, 64bit, and here we have 32bit.
Freebsd，ARM上的Linux，64位，这里我们 有32位。
They all have a short description and do different stuff.
他们都有一个简短的描述和做不同的 东西。
But we are looking for a simple execve that will execute a shell.
但我们正在寻找一个简单的执行 将执行shell。
So, why not take this one.
所以，为什么不买这个呢？
If you look at the assembler code, what it does is basically just pushing some values
如果你看汇编程序代码，它是什么？ 是基本上只是推一些价值观
on the stack, which are infact just a string that is the path /bin/sh.
在堆栈上，它只是一个字符串 这是路径/bin/sh。
And then calls execve.
然后呼叫Execve。
Copy the bytes into the python exploit script as payload and we can throw it against the
将字节复制到python漏洞脚本中 作为有效载荷，我们可以把它扔到
program.
程序。
mhmh… nothing happens.
嗯……什么都没发生。
Does it not work?
它不工作吗？
Let’s add the CC at the start of the payload if we still hit it.
让我们在有效载荷开始处添加CC 如果我们仍然击中它。
It should work.
它应该起作用。
Remove the CC againa and try it in gdb. let’s single step.
移除CC againa并在gdb中尝试。让我们 单步执行。
We are sliding down the nop slide.
我们正在滑下NOP滑道。
All seems fine.
一切似乎都很好。
And now comes the shellcode.
现在是Shellcode。
And it says: “Executing new program, /bin/dash”.
它说：“执行新程序，/bin/dash”。
That first sounds weird, but is correct.
这听起来很奇怪，但是正确的。
/bin/sh just points to /bin/dash.
/bin/sh只指向/bin/dash。
So why the hell does it not work?
为什么它不起作用？
Also on a side note.
也在旁注上。
This gdb session is no broken.
这个gdb会话没有中断。
Because execve, replaces the current program with another one.
因为execve替换了当前程序 和另一个。
So stack5 got replaced by /bin/dash.
所以stack5被/bin/dash替换。
And you can see that when you try to execute it again.
当你试图执行 再说一遍。
So you would have to load stack5 again with file.
所以你必须再次加载stack5 文件。
Ok.
好啊。
So what’s the issue then?
那么问题是什么呢？
This is one of the things I got nuts.
这是我发疯的原因之一。
When I first got stuck like this I spend houuurs trying to figure out what is happening.
当我第一次像这样被困的时候，我会花上几个小时 试图弄清楚发生了什么。
As much as I want to see anybody else suffer like me, I tell you what the problem is.
就像我想看到别人受苦一样 像我一样，我告诉你问题是什么。
A shell you execute, wants some input, right?
你执行的shell需要一些输入，对吗？
From standard input.
来自标准输入。
But!.
但是！.
We used a program and redirected it’s stdoutput into the stdinput of this program.
我们使用了一个程序并重定向了它的stdOutput 输入到这个程序的stdinput中。
And when the program was done it closed that pipe.
当程序完成后，它关闭了 管子。
So now the shell is executed, but doesn’t have any input.
所以现在shell被执行了，但是没有 有任何输入。
Because it’s closed.
因为它已经关闭了。
So it will just exit.
所以它就会退出。
And there is a neat trick to get basically around that.
还有一个简单的技巧 在这附近。
When you use cat without parameters, it simply redirect it’s stdinput to the standard output.
当您使用没有参数的cat时，它只是 将它的stdinput重定向到标准输出。
See like here.
请看这里。
You type something in, and it get’s reflected out.
你输入一些东西，它就会被反映出来 出来。
Now you can chain programs together on one line, for example with semicolon.
现在你可以把程序连在一起 行，例如分号。
So we can first print the output of the exploit, and afterwards cat is executed, so we can
所以我们可以先打印出漏洞的输出， 然后猫被处决了，所以我们可以
enter new input.
输入新输入。
And if we group that now with some brackets, and redirect their combined output into the
如果我们现在用括号来分组， 并将它们的组合输出重定向到
stack level, the exploit will first run and execute a shell, and then cat will take over
堆栈级别，漏洞将首先运行并 执行一个shell，然后cat将接管
and we can simply relay input via cat to the shell.
我们可以简单地通过CAT将输入中继到 壳牌。
BAM! it works.
巴姆！它起作用了。
We have an ugly shell, and we can verify our identity with whoami, or id.
我们有一个丑陋的外壳，我们可以验证 与whoami或id的身份。
So now we escalated privileges to root.
所以现在我们把特权升级到根目录。
Damn. feels so good.
该死。感觉很好。
It’s just beautiful.
真是太美了。